#### **CONTACT ME AT**



Arlington, Texas, 76010



josephonwu0@gmail.com



Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ joseph-onwuchekwa-9377b4255/

#### **CORE SKILLS**

- ···· Django
- ---- Django Rest Framework
- ---- Flask
- ---- Jinja
- ---- SQLAlchemy
- ---- SQL
- ···· Token Authentication (JWT)
- ---- AWS & Cloud Computing
- ···· SSL
- ---- Linux Server Administration
- ---- Apache, nginx
- ---- Unit Testing
- ---- ReactJS
- · · · · VueJS
- ---- NextJS

# EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

The University of Texas at Arlington

✓ BSC IN COMPUTER SINCE | MAY 2014

# JOSEPH ONWUCHEKWA

# **SENIOR FULL STACK ENGINEER**

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I have a strong work ethic and commitment to providing clients with products of the highest quality. I am an enthusiastic and highly motivated individual. I have strong programming and implementation skills for web application development and I see myself building high performing software in the future. I've had experience building full stack applications using Django, The Django Rest Framework, Flask on the back-end and HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, NextJS on the frontend. I've gained valuable practical experience meeting clients' business requirements and addressing needs for brand-building. I have experience successfully optimizing single-page web applications, implementing company-wide system updates to caching database queries on Redis, and serving static files from AWS S3 bucket. I am a highly versatile software engineer with the ability to write solutions for any problem.

#### MY DEVELOPMENT SKILLS

- Languages: Python, SQL, JavaScript, Typescript, HTML, CSS, Bash
- Frameworks: Django, Django REST Framework, Flask, React, NextJS, Vue, Node, Express
- Database System: PostgreSQL, MYSQL, MongoDB, AWS DynamoDB
- Version Control: Git
- UI/UX : Figma, AdobeXD, TailwindCSS, Styled components, Bootstrap
- Others: REST, AWS, Firebase, Google Cloud, Heroku, Redis, Agile(Scrum), Linode, Asana, Jira

#### MY PERSONAL SKILLS

- Able to work on my own or with a team.
- Clear and effective communication skills.
- Well thought out approach to problems.
- Ability to follow complex instructions.
- Good time management skills, prioritization skills.
- Can work efficiently with minimum supervision.
- Able to meet tight deadlines.
- Pay attention to detail.
- Willing to go the 'extra mile' to get things done.

#### **CONTACT ME AT**



Arlington, Texas, 76010



josephonwu0@gmail.com



Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in /joseph-onwuchekwa-9377b4255/

### **CORE SKILLS**

··· Django

---- Django Rest

Framework

---- Flask

---- Jinja

---- SQLAlchemy

---- SQL

•••• Token Authentication (JWT)

· · · AWS & Cloud Computing

---- SSL

---- Linux Server Administration

---- Apache, nginx

•••• Unit Testing

---- ReactJS

---- VueJS

---- NextJS

# EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

The University of Texas at Arlington

✓ BSC IN COMPUTER SINCE | MAY 2014

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Senior Full Stack Developer**

LIBERTY Dental Plan | May 2022 – May 2023

Developed a full-stack e-commerce web application from an existing Figma design using Django and Django Rest Framework on the back-end and React on the front-end. I set up the API endpoints with Django Rest Framework with private routes authenticated with JSON Web Tokens (JWT). I developed multiple Django 'apps' in this project such as Administrator Management Module, Client Module, Payment Module, and Messaging module. Redis was used as the message broker for instant messaging. During the development process, I collaborated with a team of experienced engineers and

During the development process, I collaborated with a team of experienced engineers and played a key role in improving team productivity and efficiency. I introduced and implemented new software development practices that improved code quality and reduced development time.

### **Full Stack Engineer**

Metlife | January 2018 - April 2022

During my time at Metlife, I utilized my expertise in NextJS API routes to resolve JSON Web Tokens from the Django Rest Framework (DRF) backend. This allowed secure API queries since NextJS API routes are generated on the server side. Occasionally, I used raw SQL to query the MySQL database directly instead of using the Django ORM. This allowed me to optimize the database queries and improve the speed.

Worked on multiple code bases simultaneously, committing bug fixes and pushing each to a live production environment. Implemented and executed frontend testing using React Testing Library and Jest to ensure quality and prevent regression. Also created unit tests for Django and DRF views using Coverage. I have also utilized AWS RDS to manage databases and S3 to store and manage data, ensuring data integrity and accessibility for the application.

## **Full Stack Engineer**

eBay | January 2016 - January 2018

As a Software engineer, I developed and maintained full-scale web applications from the ground up using React, Django and Django rest Framework. I connected the baack-end with a Postgresql database. I was responsible for creating responsive web pages using React and TailwindCSS. I also added new features to pre-existing web applications and pushed them to live production environments. During the development process, I built stable and maintainable codebases using MVC Architecture and Design Patterns. I played a key role in deciding some of the services' architectural choices and modeling. Furthermore, I utilized AWS to deploy and manage web applications, ensuring their scalability and security. Finally, I worked closely with project managers to meet deadlines, ensure the product fulfilled client expectations, and actively participated in sprint planning meetings using Agile methodology.

## **Software Developer**

ItechArt Group | October 2014 - January 2016

Developed dynamic and engaging web applications using HTML, CSS, Vanilla JavaScript, and Django, focusing on intuitive user interfaces and seamless user experiences. I implemented and maintained multiple backend APIs using Django Rest Framework to connect with a PostgreSQL database.

I also deployed Django back-ends on an Apache server in Linode's Ubuntu cloud servers. I set up key-based authentication for logging into the server via SSH. I installed the Uncomplicated Firewall and wrote the HTTP permissions to protect the server. I also installed the SSL certificates to make the application trustworthy.